Brecht, Arnold; Papers ger024
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Writings of Arnold Brecht, 1904-1976; 3; 198 file folders
  - Subseries 2: Essayistic and Literary Writings, 1904-1976; 3.2; 165 file folders
    - "Fifth Seat on Security Council?", 1955 January 16; clipping (photocopy) (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 28)
    - "Alvin Johnson zum 80. Geburtstage", 1955 June; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 29)
    - "Die Idee eines 'Sicherheitsgürtels'", 1955 June 4; clipping (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 30)
    - "Gangbare und ungangbare Wege. Zur Frage der Wiedervereinigung", 1955 November; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 31)
    - "Die Auflösung der Weimarer Republik und die politische Wissenschaft", 1955 December; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 32)
    - Bracher, Karl Dietrich.Die Auflösung der Weimarer Republik, 1956 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 33)
      Review by Brecht (photocopy).
    - "Gottes latenter Platz in der politischen Theorie des 20. Jahrhunderts", 1956; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 34)
    - "Wege zur Wiedervereinigung". Periodical issue containing article, 1956 January 3 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 35)
    - "Address at a Meeting in Memory of Otto Braun, Prime Minister of Republican Prussia, 1920-33", 1956 March 21 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 36)
      Text of speech (photocopy).
    - "The Present and Future Position of the Graduate Faculty", ca. 1957; typescript (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 37)
    - Friedrich, Carl J. and Zbigniew Brzesinski.Totalitarian Dictatorship and Autocracy (1956), Winter 1957 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 38)
      Review by Brecht, reprint.
    - "Bürokratie", 1957; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 39)
    - Wolf, Eric.Das Problem der Naturrechtslehre: Versuch einer Orientierung (1955), 1958 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 40)
    - Ross, Alf.On Law and Justice (1959), 1960 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 41)
    - "Civil Service in the U.S". Weinheim Conference, 1950 December 1-1950 December 3 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 42)
    - "Funeral Service for Edith Johnson (Mrs. Alvin Johnson), Nyack, N.Y., February 28, 1961". Text of Brecht's eulogy, Undated; photocopy (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 43)
    - "Fairness in Foreign Policy: The Chinese Issue", Spring 1961; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 44)
    - Stolper, Toni.Ein Leben in Brennpunkten unserer Zeit (1960), Summer 1961 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 45)
    - Studies in Legal Philosophy. Ed. William R. Andersen (Dec. 1960), 1961 September (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 46)
    - "Berlin. Forum at the New School for Social Research, October 31, 1961", Undated; typescript, photocopy (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 47)
    - Catlin, George E. Gordon.Systematic Politics, Elementa Politica et Sociologica (1962). Text of review by Brecht, Undated (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 48)
    - " Liberty and Truth: The Responsibility of Science", 1962 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 49)
      Photocopy of book chapter.
    - "Die Tröstungen der strengen Wissenschaft", 1962; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 50)
    - "Regional Differences of Political Opinion in Germany". Speech text, 1962 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 51)
    - "The 'New Political Science' Reexamined: A Symposium", Summer 1962; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 52)
    - "Standards of Justice -- A Note on Their Validity", 1962 July; typescript (photocopy) (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 53)
    - "Address to Graduate Students and Junior Instructors", 1962 September 7 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 54)
      Text of lecture (photocopy) for American Political Science Association meeting.
    - "In Honor of Ernst Spiegelberg. September 14, 1962", Undated (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 55)
      Text of memorial speech (photocopy).
    - "Some Remarks on the Scientific Examination of Political Goals", 1962 October 17 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 56)
      Text of lecture (photocopy).
    - "The Ultimate Standard of Justice", 1963 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 57)
    - "Sehr verehrter Herr Kesten". Text of letter to the editor, 1963 January 14 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 58)
    - "Alvin Johnson's 89th birthday, December 18, 1963. New School Associates Dinner". Text of speech, Undated; photocopy (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 59)
    - Anderson, William.Man's Quest for Political Knowledge -- The Study and Teaching of Politics in Ancient Times, 1964 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 60)
      Typescript of review by Brecht (photocopy).
    - "Lübeck in der Reichsreform", 1965; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 61)
    - "Re: Verjähung von Naziverbrechen". Letter to the editor (photocopy), 1965 January 22 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 62)
    - "Gedanken über den Verlust einer prodemokratischen Mehrheit unter einer demokratischen Staatsverfassung", 1966; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 63)
    - "Memorial Meeting Frieda Wunderlich, Mar. 12, 1966", Undated (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 64)
      Typescript of memorial essay (photocopy).
    - "Mein religiöses Leben. Aus der Lebenserinnerungen". Periodical issue with essay, 1967 February (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 65)
    - "Political Theory", 1968; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 66)
      Also original draft of entry for International Encyclopedia of Social Science (1963).
    - "Acceptance as 'Fact' and the Concept of Truth and Logical Reasoning", 1969 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 67)
      Text of reprinted chapter from Political Theory.
    - "Gedanken über Brünings Memoiren" (review by Brecht of Heinrich Brüning Memoiren 1918-1934), 1971; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 68)
    - "Erich Hula: Some Remarks on the Man and His Work", Summer 1971; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 69)
    - "Akademische Freiheit und Politisierung der Hochschulen". Text of lecture written with Hans Staudinger, 1972 April (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 70)
      Also correspondence.
    - "Speech on the Conference in Honor of Professor Adolf Lowe's 80th birthday, March 2, 1973", Undated (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 71)
    - Draft of untitled speech, 1973 August (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 72)
    - The Legacy of the German Refugee Intellectuals. Ed. Robert Boyers (1972), 1973 December (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 73)
    - "The Monitoring Role of Democracy", 1974 (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 74)
      Typescript of article for Recasens Festschrift.
    - "On the Presumed Dullness of the Fact-Value Controversy", 1974; typescript (photocopy) (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 75)
    - "In Memoriam Carl Mayer", 1974; typescript (photocopy) (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 76)
    - "A Note on Alfred Schuetz", 1975 March; typescript (photocopy) (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 77)
      Also correspondence, 1974-1975.
    - "The Incompatibility of Liberty and Equality", 1976; reprint (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 78)
    - "Justice -- traditional, transtraditional and absolute", Undated; handwritten text (photocopy) (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 79)
    - "The Latent Place of God in Twentieth Century Political Theory", Undated; mimeographed text (Box 11 (3-Writings of Arnold Brecht), Folder 80)
- Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on Various Lecture Topics, 1935-1963; 4; 101 file folders
  This series contains lecture notes, clippings and other course materials used by Brecht in his courses and seminars primarily at the New School for Social Research, Harvard University, and the University of Heidelberg.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - "A -- J", Undated; handwritten notes (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 1-2)
  - "K -- O", Undated; handwritten notes (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 3)
  - "P -- Z", Undated; handwritten notes (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 4)
  - Bibliographies for courses and seminars, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 5)
  - Examination questions, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous lecture notes, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 7)
  - British Parliament, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 8)
    Notes, clippings.
  - Bureaucracy/Bürokratie, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 9)
  - "Changes in Democratic Institutions" / "Is Democracy going Fascist?" -- lecture notes, 1938 July 8 (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 10)
  - Civil Service. Lecture notes, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 11)
  - Civil Service and Public Administration, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 12)
    Notes and clippings.
  - "Coincidence of Political and Economic Systems", Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 13)
  - Commerce Clause / Anti-trust / Public Administration, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 14)
  - Anti-trust, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 15)
  - Comparative Administration / Government in Economics. Seminar notes, Harvard, 1937 (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 16)
  - Comparative Government, 1936; 1938 (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 17)
  - Comparative Government, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 18)
  - Comparative Government, 1957-1958 (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 19)
  - Comparative Public Administration of Germany, Great Britain and France, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 20)
  - Comparative War Administration, 1940s (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 21)
  - Due Process, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 22)
  - Due Process, United States, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 23)
  - Efficiency and Individual Rights, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 24)
  - "Ends of the State: Aufgabe, Zweck, Ziel". Early English lecture notes, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 25)
  - "Entwurf einer politischen Richtlinie für deutsche Ostpolitik", 1963 (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 26)
  - "Error, Guild and Falsehood", ca. 1940 (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 27)
  - Existentialism (Sartre), 1960 (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 28)
    Notes, clipping.
  - Federalism and Business Regulation. Seminar notes, Undated (Box 12 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 29)
  - Finances, New York and U.S., Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 1)
  - Finances (2), Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 2)
  - Forms of Government, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 3)
  - France, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 4-5)
  - "General Will". General Welfare, notes, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 6)
  - Germany, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 7-8)
  - Germany, 1950s (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 9)
  - Government. Course notes, ca. 1940 (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 10)
  - Government in Economics. Course notes, 1937; Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 11)
  - Government and Economics, Anarchy, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 12)
  - Great Britain, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 13)
  - Great Britain, United States and France, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 14)
  - Heidelberg, 1952; 1954 (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 15)
    Lecture notes.
  - History of the United States, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 16)
  - Human Rights (Menschenrechte). Notes, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 17)
  - Impossibility/Unmöglichkeit, 1959 (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 18)
    Notes, Heidelberg.
  - Incompatibility of Liberty and Equality, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 19)
  - Indians, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 20)
  - Justice. Lecture notes, 1936 (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 21)
  - Justice, 1937 (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 22)
  - "Long-range Planning in Democracy". Lecture and seminar notes, 1936-1937 (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 23)
  - Majority, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 24)
  - Mathematical notations, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 25)
  - "The Meaning of 'Constitution'", Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 26)
  - Meaning of Democracy, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 27)
  - Meaning of History, 1951-1955; Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 28)
  - "Missverständnisse: 1) im Ausland über Deutschland 2) in Deutschland über Amerika", 1954 (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 29)
  - Municipal Governments, especially Germany, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 30)
  - Nationalization, Corporations, Undated (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 31)
  - Political Goals, 1962-1963 (Box 13 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 32)
  - Political Machinery in a Democracy. Seminar notes, 1936 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 1)
  - Political Science and the Sense of Justice. Seminar notes, 1936 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 2)
  - Political Science. Course notes, 1935-1937 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 3)
  - Political Science lectures, 1936-1937 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 4)
  - "The Political Sphere (Science, Choice, Action)". Seminar notes, 1941 October (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 5)
  - Political Theory Today, Fall 1959 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 6)
  - Public Administration, 1937 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 7)
  - Public Administration, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 8)
  - Public Corportations, U.S. Economic Policy, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 9)
  - "Public Expenditures and Density of Population", 1941 March (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 10)
  - "Purges 1937-38", Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 11)
  - The Racial Problem, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 12)
  - Rathenau's 100th birthday, 1967 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 13)
  - Rival Forms of Government, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 14)
  - Russia, 1947-1948 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 15)
  - Science for Democracy, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 16)
  - Scientific Political Theory. Lecture notes, 1956-1957 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 17)
  - Sovereignty, Relation of the Individual to the State, Natural Law, Political Interpretation of History, 1937 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 18)
  - Sovereignty. Seminar notes, 1938 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 19)
  - State, definitions, 1936-1937 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 20)
  - State and sovereignty, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 21)
  - U.S. Crossroads Behind and Crossroads Ahead, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 22)
  - U.S. History and government, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 23)
  - U.S. Treasury, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 24)
  - "Value Questions in Current Events", 1953 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 25)
  - Vocabulary lists, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 26)
  - Weltrelativismus, 1959 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 27)
  - Wissenschaft und Politisches Handeln, 1955 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 28)
  - "Woodrow Wilson -- Congressional Government", Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 29)
  - The World's Constitutional History. Introduction, Bibliography. Heidelberg lectures, 1955-1956 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 30)
  - The World's Constitutional History: Athens, Sparta, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 31)
  - The World's Constitutional History: Feudalism, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 32)
  - The World's Constitutional History: France, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 33-35)
  - The World's Constitutional History: Germany, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 36)
  - The World's Constitutional History: Great Britain, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 37)
  - The World's Constitutional History: Great Britain, after 1918, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 38)
  - The World's Constitutional History: Rome, Undated (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 39)
  - The World's Constitutional History: History of U.S. Constitution. Heidelberg lectures, 1955-1956 (Box 14 (4-Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Clippings on V), Folder 40)
- Writings by Others, 1939-1974; 5; 31 file folders
  This series contains typescripts of articles by colleagues of Brecht, especially by and about other New School members. Included in the series are papers read at the New School for Social Research Fortieth Anniversary Bonn Conference, June 20-21, 1974.
  - Democracy -- student definitions, Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 1)
  - American Committee for Liberation, Inc. "Soviet Attitudes As Reported by Recent Visitors to the USSR", 1959 October 1 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 2)
  - Appleby, Paul H. "Public Administration in India. Report of a Survey", 1953 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 3)
  - Ascoli, Max. "To the Members of the Graduate Faculty". Peace Research Project, 1939 December (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 4)
  - Bailey, H. S. Jr. "For Arnold Brecht". Poem, dedicated to Brecht, 1962 April 23 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 5)
  - Brecht, Gustav. "Die Schicksalsformel unserer Wirtschaft", 1921 October 14; clipping (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 6)
  - Clapp, Gordon R. Six lectures on the Tennessee Valley Authority, 1954 February 15-1954 February 16 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 7)
  - Corning, Peter A. "The Biological Bases of Behavior and Some Implications for Political Science". Partial text, Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 8)
  - Hula, Erich. "Fifty Years of International Government. Relexions on the League of Nations and the United Nations", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 9)
  - Hula, Erich. "Leo Strauss", 1974 October 18 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 10)
  - Lohmann, Friedrich. "Das Ende des Kapp-Putsches. Eine Erinnerung an Reichspräsident Ebert", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 11)
  - Lowe, Adolph. "Conflicting Paradigms in Economics. A Self-Critique", 1973 March (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 12)
  - Luhmann, Niklas. "The Legal Profession: Comments on the Situation in the Federal Republic of Germany", 1974 May (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 13)
  - Luhmann, Niklas. "Rechtsprechung als professionelle Praxis", 1975 December (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 14)
  - Macridis, Roy C. "New Approaches in the Study of European Governments. The Study of Political Consensus", 1955 August 1 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 15)
  - Mayer, Carl. "The University in Exile", Summer 1939 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 16)
  - Mayer, Carl, Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 17)
    Reprints, clippings by.
  - Mayer, Carl. Articles about, Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 18)
  - Schlözer, Leopold von. "Aus der Jugendzeit", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 19)
  - Staudinger, Hans. "Kurt Grossmann 1897-1972", 1972 June 29 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 20)
  - Staudinger, Hans. "Staudinger Comments on Heilbroner", 1972 December 12 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 21)
  - White, Howard. "[Leo Strauss]", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 22)
  - Wilk, Gerard. "University-in-Exile", 1976 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 23)
  - Papers from the New School for Social Research Fortieth Anniversary Bonn Conference, 1974 June 20-1974 June 21; 5.24 (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 24-31)
    - Baudissin, Wolf Graf von. "Changes in the Meaning of Military and Political Concepts of Peace", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 24)
    - Laqueur, Walter. "Lost Illusions: the End of the Post-War World?", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 25)
    - Marshall, Charles Burton. "Changing Concepts of Peace: An American Focus", Undated (Box 15 (5-Writings by Others), Folder 26)